(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Loyalty To Luna
Himemori Luna Birthday Live
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
そういう扱い　心得て
Make sure you understand how to treat me like one
よね！
Right!
ワールドイズマイン
作詞・作曲 ryo(supercell)
World Is Mine
Lyrics & Composition: ryo(supercell)
その一　いつもと違う髪形に気がつくこと
Number one: Notice when my hairstyle is different from usual
その二　ちゃんと靴まで見ること　いいね？
Number two: Make sure you look all the way down to my shoes, okay?
その三　私の一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Number three: Answer every word I say with three words
わかったら右手が留守なのをなんとかして！
If you understand, do something about my empty right hand!
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm saying I'm selfish or anything
キミに心から思って欲しいの　かわいいって
I just want you to think from the bottom of your heart that I'm cute
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world
気がついて　ねえねえ
Notice me, hey, hey
待たせるなんて論外よ
Keeping me waiting is out of the question
わたしを誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もう！
Geez!
ワールドイズマイン
World is Mine
甘いものが食べたい！
I want to eat something sweet!
今すぐによ
Right now!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょう
Defects? You must mean cute.
文句は許しませんの
No complaints allowed.
あのね、私の話ちゃんと聞いてる？
Hey, are you listening to me properly?
ちょっと
Hey!
あ、それとね
Oh, and another thing.
白いお馬さん、決まってるでしょう
A white horse, it's already decided.
迎えに来て
Come pick me up.
わかったら かしずいて手を取って
If you understand, kneel down and take my hand,
「お姫様」って
and call me "Princess."
別にわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything.
でもね、少し位叱ってくれたっていいのよ
But you know, it's okay to scold me just a little bit.
世界で私だけのおうじさま
My one and only prince in the world.
気がついて ほらほら
Notice me, look, look,
おててが空いてます
my hand is free.
無口で無愛想なおうじさま
My quiet and unsociable prince.
もう、どうして！気がついてよ早く
Geez, why! Notice me already!
あっ
Ah!
絶対君はわかってない！
You definitely don't understand!
わかってないわ...
You don't understand...
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
Strawberry shortcake,
こだわりたまごのとろけるプリン
and melting pudding made with special eggs.
みんなみんな我慢します...
I'll endure it all...
わがままな子だと思わないで
Please don't think I'm a selfish girl.
私だってやればできるもん
I can do it if I try.
あとで後悔するわよ
You'll regret it later!
当然です！だって私は
Of course! Because I'm the
世界で一番おひめさま
number one princess in the world.
ちゃんと見ててよね
Keep your eyes on me,
どこかに行っちゃうよ
or I'll go somewhere else.
ふいに抱きしめられた
I was suddenly embraced.
急にそんな、えっ？
All of a sudden, what?
「惹かれる 危ないよ」
"I'm drawn to you. It's dangerous,"
そう言ってそっぽ向く君
you say, looking away.
...こっちのが危ないわよ
...this is more dangerous.
な！
Na!
Hey, baby!
うなあああ！
Unaaaa!
んーなあああい！みんなおはよー！
Nnaaaai! Good morning, everyone!
ホロライブ4期生、姫森ルーナなんなあああい！
Hololive 4th Gen, Himemori Luna-nnaaaai!
今日はなんと、ルーナの
Today is actually
誕生日なんならやー！わーい！
Luna's birthday-nna raya! Yay!
ということでね、今日はこちらの
So, I want you to tweet a lot with the
「#姫森ルーナ誕生祭2022」
hashtag "#HimemoriLunaBirthday2022"
いっぱいツイートしてほしいならやー！
today-naya!
そして、みんな気になっていると思う、
And, I'm going to introduce this stage
このステージを紹介してくならやー！
that I'm sure you're all curious about-naya!
まずは...
First...
あれ、ルーナイト？お前...
Wait, Lu-knight? You...
3Dになってんじゃねーかよ！
You've become 3D!
おい、ルーナイト、ちょっとこっち来いよ。
Hey, Lu-knight, come here a bit.
ちょっとこっち来いよ。おいおいおい。
Come here a bit. Hey, hey, hey.
ルーナイト、お前そこから動けへんのか、ルーナイト。
Lu-knight, can't you move from there, Lu-knight?
でも見て、可愛いルーナイト。
But look, cute Lu-knight.
とうとう平面から3Dになったのらね。
You finally went from 2D to 3D-nora.
旗持って、そこでじゃあ見ておいてほしいのらよ、ルーナイト。
Hold the flag and just watch from there, Lu-knight.
そして、え？なんだこれ？
And, eh? What's this?
う、え？かんざきパパ？
Uh, eh? Kanzaki-papa?
パパがたこさんのメリーゴーランド...
Papa is on a Takosan merry-go-round...
なんなのこれ。スピードが...え、パパ！
what is this. The speed is... eh, Papa!
パパ大丈夫？そのスピードついていけてる？
Papa, are you okay?
パパ。
Can you keep up with that speed? Papa.
やばい、これすげーのらね、
Whoa, this is amazing-nora,
めっちゃ可愛いのらよ。
it's so cute.
う、笑っちゃ、笑っちゃうかもしんないけど...
I, I might end up laughing, but...
パパ大丈夫？めっちゃ可愛い、めっちゃね、たこ焼きでね。
Papa, are you okay? So cute, so many Takoyaki.
すごい作り込んでくれたのらよ。
They really put a lot of work into this-nora.
パパの顔どんな...どんななってんだ、これ。
What does Papa's face... what does it look like.
アップで、アップで見れますか？
Can we get an up... an up-close look?
パパ...！いつも通りの顔だったな。
Papa...! He has his usual face.
めちゃくちゃ可愛くね？このステージも作っていただきました！
Isn't it super cute? They made this stage for me too!
わー！ライトもすげーのら、はしゃ、はしゃいでる！
Wow! The lights are amazing-nora, they're so lively!
誕生祭だからな、めちゃくちゃパパもお祝いしてくれてるのな！
Since it's my birthday celebration, Papa is celebrating a lot too!
そして、見て！お城、凄い3Dの立体的になってるのなよ。
And, look! The castle, it's become an amazing 3D structure.
見て見て見て！ジャジャーン！
Look, look, look! Ta-da!
すげーのなよ。え、あの辺ルーナたんのお部屋じゃねーのな？
It's amazing! Hey, isn't that area around there Luna-tan's room?
え、凄すぎなのなよ！
Whoa, it's too amazing!
ね、「Loyalty」って書いてあるでしょ。これめっちゃ可愛いのな。
See, it says "Loyalty", right? This is so cute.
配信のね、スタンプでLTL... LTL...
You know, the stream stamps, LTL... LTL...
「Loyalty To Luna」のね、そこから今日こちらのタイトルにさせてもらったのなよ。
From "Loyalty To Luna", I made it today's title.
めっちゃ可愛い！
So cute!
そして、右の方と左の上の方に... なんかルーナイトの紋章が見えるのなね。
And, on the right and top left... I can see some Lu-Knight crests.
旗がね、はためいちゃってるのなよー！
The flags are fluttering!
可愛い。可愛いね、ルーナイトの紋章も。
Cute. The Lu-Knight crests are cute too.
こちらも可愛いのを作っていただきました。
These were made cute for me as well.
そして...
And...
ん？ちょっと待つのな...
Hmm? Wait a second...
あれ？ルーナイト？
Huh? Lu-Knight?
お前... お前3Dになったのか！
You... You've become 3D!
え、まさか... 持てる！
Wait, could it be... I can hold you!
やべーのな！
This is crazy!
ルーナイト？ルーナイトなの？ルーナイト生きてんのかこれ。
Lu-Knight? Is it a Lu-Knight? Is this Lu-Knight alive?
あ、動い... え、お前生きてんのか？
Oh, it's mov... Eh, you're alive?
生きてるよルーナイト！
He's alive, Lu-Knight!
姫様... 姫様...
Princess... Princess...
私とうとう、とうとうルーナイトは3Dになりました。
I have finally, finally become a 3D Lu-Knight.
お前喋れるのかよ！可愛い！
You can talk?! So cute!
パパがね、デザインしてくれたこちらルーナイトも。
Papa designed this Lu-Knight too.
ルーナイトもね、今日のために3Dになってお披露目なのなー！
Lu-Knight has become 3D and is making its debut today too!
今日はね、このルーナイトたちと、海月パパと、
Today, with these Lu-Knights, Kurage-papa, and
この素敵なお城のステージで...
on this wonderful castle stage...
ルーナたん歌って踊っていきたいと思うのな！
Luna-tan is going to sing and dance!
ゲストもね、たくさん呼んでいるので
I've invited lots of guests too, so
最後まで楽しんでいって欲しいのなよー！
I want you to enjoy it until the end!
ふわふわ時間 / 歌：姫森ルーナ、猫又おかゆ / 作詞：秋山澪 / 作曲：前澤寛之
Fuwa Fuwa Time / Vocals: Himemori Luna, Nekomata Okayu / Lyrics: Akiyama Mio / Composition: Maezawa Hiroyuki
君を見てるといつもハートDOKI DOKI
Whenever I look at you, my heart is always pounding
揺れる思いはマシュマロみたいにふわふわ
My swaying feelings are soft and fluffy like marshmallows
いつもがんばる
Always doing your best
君の横顔
Looking at your profile
ずっと見てても気づかないよね
You don't notice even if I keep looking
夢の中なら
If it's inside a dream
二人の距離
The distance between us
縮められるのにな
Could be shortened, though...
あぁ神様お願い
Ah, God, please
二人だけの
A "Dream Time"
ドリームタイムください
For just the two of us, please
お気に入りのうさちゃん抱いて
Holding my favorite bunny
今夜もおやすみ
Good night tonight, too
ふとした拍子に今日もハートDOKI DOKI
By some chance, today too, my heart is pounding
さりげない笑顔 深読みしすぎてオーバーヒート
Over-analyzing your casual smile and overheating
いつか目にした
The face of yours
君のマジ顔
That I saw once with a serious expression
瞳閉じても浮かんでくるよ
Even when I close my eyes, it floats up
夢でいいから
Even if it's just a dream
二人だけの
A "Sweet Time"
スウィートタイムほしいの
For just the two of us, I want
あぁ神様どうして
Ah, God, why
好きになるほど
The more I come to like you
ドリームナイト切ないの
The more painful the "Dream Night" becomes
とっておきのくまちゃん抱いて
Holding my special teddy bear
今夜は大丈夫かな
I wonder if I'll be okay tonight
窓をそっと開けて
Gently opening the window...
自然に話せば
if I speak naturally...
何かが変わるのかな
I wonder if something will change.
そんな気がするけど
I feel like it would, but...
だけど それが一番 難しいのよ
But that's the hardest part of all.
話のきっかけとか どうしよう
How should I even start a conversation?
てか 段取り考えてる時点で
Actually, the fact that I'm planning it...
全然 自然じゃないよね
means it's not natural at all, right?
あぁ もう 寝ちゃお 寝ちゃお 寝ちゃお!
Ah, forget it! I'm going to sleep, sleep, sleep!
そう寝ちゃお!
Yeah, I'm sleeping!
あぁ 神様お願い 一度だけ
Ah, God, please, just for once...
ミラクルタイムをください
please give me a miracle time.
もし すんなり話せれば
If I could just talk to you smoothly...
その後は どうにかなるよね
then everything after that would work out.
ふわふわタイム
Fuwa Fuwa Time
Los! Los! Los!
作詞:hotaru 作曲:八木雄一
Lyrics: hotaru / Composition: Yuichi Yagi
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los! Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Fire! Barrage! Go! Attention! Cover! Down! Halt!
戦場へ 前線へ そして死の地まで
To the battlefield, to the front lines, and to the land of death!
命捨てた その覚悟を示せ
Show your resolve to discard your life!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los! Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Fire! Barrage! Go! Attention! Cover! Down! Halt!
聞こえるだろう あの咆哮が
You can hear it, can't you? That roar...
抵抗する 蛆の声が
...the voices of maggots resisting!
踏みつぶせ
Crush them!
諸君、我々の任務は何だ？
Gentlemen, what is our mission?
殲滅だ！
Annihilation!
一匹残らずの殲滅だ！
Annihilation of every single one!
成すべきことは ただ一つ！
There is only one thing to do!
地獄を創れ！
Create a hell!
弾丸の雨に打たれにゆくのか
Will you walk into a rain of bullets?
嘲笑せよ 国家のために
Laugh in their faces, for the sake of the nation!
戦場へ 前線へ そして死の地まで
To the battlefield, to the front lines, and to the land of death!
命捨てた 覚悟を示せよ
Show your resolve to discard your life!
忠誠を 従順を そしてその魂を
Your loyalty, your obedience, and your soul...
全て捧げ 勝ち鬨をあげよ
give it all and raise a victory cry!
さあ ここに築いてみせろ
Now, build it right here for me...
天に届く 屍の山を
...a mountain of corpses reaching the heavens!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los! Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Fire! Barrage! Go! Attention! Cover! Down! Halt!
どこに恐怖が あるというのだ
Where is this "fear" you speak of?
見ろ血肉が 花火のようだ
Look, the flesh and blood are like fireworks!
撒き散らせ
Scatter them!
戦の傷跡は 忘れちゃいないさ
We haven't forgotten the scars of battle.
おののけ 雲霞 溢れた屠殺場
Tremble! A slaughterhouse teeming like a cloud of insects!
最後の一撃に 濁った瞳に
In that final groan, in those clouded eyes...
あぁ それこそ 求めるのだ
ah, that is exactly what we seek!
安寧も 平穏も 待っちゃいないさ
Neither peace nor tranquility are waiting.
希望を捨てた 背信の将校
A treacherous officer who abandoned hope.
絶望と 怒号を吐いた 狂気の沙汰は
This madness, spitting out despair and roars...
地獄よりも 楽園のようだ
is more of a paradise than hell.
その死屍は 踊るために
Those corpses are for dancing...
踊り狂う ためにあるのだ
they exist to dance madly!
人間に価値などない
Humans have no value.
価値なき者同士の争いに 命の徒花を咲かせてみせろ
In a struggle between valueless things, make the empty flowers of life bloom!
法律も 秩序でも
Laws or order...
狂った奴が 作っている
they're all made by the insane.
まさにワルツ 不条理だけの
It's truly a waltz of sheer absurdity...
起承転結
...from beginning to end.
戦場へ 前線へ そして死の地まで
To the battlefield, to the front lines, and to the land of death!
命捨てた 覚悟を示せ
Show your resolve to discard your life!
忠誠を 従順を そしてその魂を
Your loyalty, your obedience, and your soul...
全て捧げ 勝ち鬨をあげよ
give it all and raise a victory cry!
さあ ここに築いてみせろ
Now, build it right here for me...
天に届く 屍の山を
...a mountain of corpses reaching the heavens!
谺する 憎しみさえ
Even the echoing hatred...
掻き消す爆発音
is drowned out by the sound of explosions!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los! Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Fire! Barrage! Go! Attention! Cover! Down! Halt!
こちら、幸福安心委員会です。
作詞：鳥居羊　作曲：うたたP
This is the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee.
Lyrics: Hitsuji Torii / Composition: UtataP
どうして　みんなが　幸せなの？
Why is everyone so happy?
この世界のこと
About this world...
聞きたいって　知りたいって
I want to hear, I want to know.
三つ目の声で
With the voice of the third eye,
みんなが耳を澄ませて
everyone is listening closely.
ワクワクするね
How exciting it is!
ねぇオンディーヌ
Right, Ondine?
ハイハイ！
Hi-hi!
さぁさぁ皆様教えてあげます！
Now, now everyone, I shall tell you!
みんなが気になっていること、疑問に思っていること、
Everything you're curious about, everything you're wondering about,
全部教えてあげます！
I shall tell you everything!
さぁ皆様は幸福なのは義務なんです。
Now, everyone, being happy is a duty.
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ？
It's a duty, you know?
果たしてますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
我々幸福安心委員会は、皆様の幸せを願い、
We, the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee, wish for your happiness,
そして支えます。
and support you.
幸福なのは義務なんです　幸福なのは義務なんです
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is a duty! Being happy is a duty!
Being happy is a duty!
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ？
It's a duty, you know?
幸福なのは義務なんです　幸福なのは義務なんです
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is a duty! Being happy is a duty!
Being happy is a duty!
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ！
It's a duty!
ですから、安心して義務を果たすように！
Therefore, please fulfill your duty with peace of mind!
皆様の幸せが我々の幸せ。
Your happiness is our happiness.
幸せですか？義務ですよ？果たしてますか？
Are you happy? It's a duty, you know? Are you fulfilling it?
幸せじゃないなら...
If you aren't happy...
絞首 斬首 銃殺 釜茹で 溺死 電撃 火あぶり 生き埋め
薬殺 石打ち 鋸挽き 磔
Hanging, Decapitation, Firing Squad, Boiling, Drowning, Electrocution,
Burning, Burying Alive, Lethal Injection, Stoning, Sawing, Crucifixion.
好きなの選んでね！
Choose the one you like!
ハイハイ！
Hi-hi!
さぁさぁ皆様幸せだけが満ちてます！
Now, now everyone, only happiness is overflowing!
不安とか不満、何一つないでしょう？
Anxiety or dissatisfaction, there isn't a single one, right?
こわい、こわいわ！
It's scary, so scary!
幸せすぎてこわいわ！
It's so happy it's scary!
本当にみんなが幸せなの？
Is everyone really happy?
この世界のそと
Outside of this world...
いきたいって　にげたいって
I want to go, I want to run away.
三つ目の声で
With the voice of the third eye,
みんなが耳をふさいで
everyone is covering their ears.
ビクビクしてた
They were trembling.
ねぇオンディーヌ
Right, Ondine?
ハイハイ！
Hi-hi!
さぁさぁ皆様死にました！
Now, now everyone, you're dead!
オンディーヌ様たちは死にました！
The Ondines have died!
葬儀にでるなら向こうに並べ、
If you're attending the funeral, line up over there,
それ以外は幸せに暮らせ！
otherwise, live happily!
以上！
That's all!
幸福なのは義務なんです　幸福なのは義務なんです
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is a duty! Being happy is a duty!
Being happy is a duty!
幸せですか？義務ですよ？
Are you happy? It's a duty, you know?
幸福なのは義務なんです　幸福なのは義務なんです
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is a duty! Being happy is a duty!
Being happy is a duty!
幸せですか？義務ですよ。
Are you happy? It's a duty.
義務なんです。義務ですよ。
It's a duty. It's a duty, you know.
義務なんです。幸福なのは義務なんです。
It's a duty. Being happy is a duty.
義務なんです。義務ですよ。義務なんです。
It's a duty. It's a duty, you know. It's a duty.
幸せじゃないなら、死ね。
If you aren't happy, die.
さあいくよ！
Here we go!
1, 2, 3!
桃色片想い
作詞・作曲：つんく
Peach Colored Unrequited Love
Lyrics & Composition: Tsunku
桃色の片想い 恋してる
A pink one-sided love, I'm in love
マジマジと見つめてる
I'm staring intently
チラチラと目があえば
If our eyes meet every now and then
胸がキュルルン 桃色の片想い
My heart goes flutter, a pink one-sided love
片想いらしい片想いなんて 初めてしちゃいます
This is the first time I've had a real one-sided love
わかんないことがわかんないくらい 好きみたいです
I seem to like you so much I don't know what I don't know
あの人に (wow wow wow wow...)
That person (wow wow wow wow...)
恋びとしているのかな？
I wonder if they have a lover?
夢にだって (wow wow wow wow...)
Even in my dreams (wow wow wow wow...)
出ちゃってきちゃいます 今以上気になっちゃう
You keep showing up, I'm getting even more curious now
桃色の片想いしちゃってる
I'm having a pink one-sided love
知らぬ間にしちゃってる
I've fallen into it before I knew it
偶然に出会ってる
Meeting by chance
胸がキュルルン
My heart goes flutter
桃色の片想い 恋してる
A pink one-sided love, I'm in love
マジマジと見つめてる
I'm staring intently
チラチラと目があえば
If our eyes meet every now and then
胸がキュルルン 桃色の片想い
My heart goes flutter, a pink one-sided love
誘えない とっても誘えない お天気の話しちゃいます
I can't invite you, I really can't, so I talk about the weather
わかってそうでわかってん ここがココロときめ
I think I understand but I don't, my heart is racing here
気合い入れて (te te te te...)
Getting fired up (te te te te...)
話しかけましょう
Let's go talk to them
勇気だして (te te te te...)
Mustering up my courage (te te te te...)
こんにちは そく さよなら 会話になってない なってない
Hello, then immediately goodbye, it's not even a conversation
桃色の片想いしてるけど
I'm having a pink one-sided love, but
両想い目指すけど
Even though I'm aiming for mutual love
昨日より近付いた
I got closer than yesterday
胸がキュルルン
My heart goes flutter
桃色の片想い キスしてる
A pink one-sided love, I'm kissing you
マジマジと夢見てる
I'm dreaming intently
あなたには見えますか
Can you see it?
恋の色が
The color of love
桃色の季節
The pink season
桃色の片想いしちゃってる
I'm having a pink one-sided love
知らぬ間にしちゃってる
I've fallen into it before I knew it
偶然に出会ってる
Meeting by chance
胸がキュルルン
My heart goes flutter
桃色の片想い 恋してる
A pink one-sided love, I'm in love
マジマジと見つめてる
I'm staring intently
チラチラと目があえば
If our eyes meet every now and then
胸がキュルルン 桃色の片想い
My heart goes flutter, a pink one-sided love
正しさとは
What is righteousness?
愚かさとは
What is foolishness?
それが何か
Exactly what they are
見せつけてやる
I'll show you
ちっちゃな頃から優等生
I've been a model student since I was small
気づいたら大人になってた
Before I knew it, I'd become an adult
ナイフのような思考回路
A knife-like thought process
持ち合わせる訳もなく
Is something I obviously don't have
でも遊び足りない 何か足りない
But I haven't played enough, something is missing
困っちまうこれは誰かのせい
It's troubling, this is someone else's fault
あてもなくただ混乱するエイデイ
Just aimlessly confused every day
それもそっか 最新の流行は当然の把握
I guess so, naturally I'm on top of the latest trends
経済
The economy
I'm a girl coming from the kingdom, Nanora.
純情な精神で入社しワーク
With a pure spirit, I joined the company and worked
社会人じゃ当然のルールです
It's a natural rule for a member of society
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
あなたが思うより健康です
I'm healthier than you think
一切合切凡庸な
Everything, entirely, is mediocre
あなたじゃ分からないかもね
You probably wouldn't understand
嗚呼よく似合う
Ah, it suits you well
その可もなく不可もないメロディー
That melody that's neither good nor bad
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
頭の出来が違うので問題はナシ
My brain is built differently, so there's no problem
つっても私も人間
Even so, I'm only human
殴ったりするのはノーセンキュー
Hitting people is a "no thank you"
だったら言葉の銃口を
In that case, the muzzle of my words
その頭に突きつけて撃てば
I'll press it to your head and fire
煩わしい 止まれやしない
It's annoying, it won't stop
不平不満垂れて夜の果て
Spouting complaints until the end of the night
サディスティックに変貌する精神
A spirit that transforms sadistically
クソだりーな 酒が空いたグラスあればすぐに注ぎなさい
So damn tiring, if there's an empty glass, pour the sake immediately
皆がつまみやすいように串外しなさい
Remove the skewers so everyone can snack easily
会計や注文は先陣を切る
Take the lead in ordering and paying the bill
不文律最低限のマナーです
It's the bare minimum of unwritten manners
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
くせぇ口塞げや限界です
Shut your stinking mouth, I'm at my limit
絶対絶対現代の代弁者は私やろがい
I'm absolutely, definitely the spokesperson for the modern age!
もう見飽きたわ 二番煎じ言い換えのパロディ
I'm sick of seeing it, a second-hand, rephrased parody
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
丸々と肉付いたその顔面にバツ
An X on that plump, fleshy face of yours
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
私が俗に言う天才です
I am what they commonly call a genius
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
あなたが思うより健康です
I'm healthier than you think
一切合切凡庸な
Everything, entirely, is mediocre
あなたじゃ分からないかもね
You probably wouldn't understand
嗚呼つまらねぇ
Ah, how boring
何回聞かせればそのメモリー
How many times must I hear that memory?
うっせぇ うっせぇ うっせぇわ
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
アタシも大概だけどどうだっていいぜ問題はナシ
I'm pretty bad too, but who cares, there's no problem
よみがえれ
Revive!
Over Soul
作詞：MEGUMI 作曲：たかはしごう
Lyrics: MEGUMI Composition: Takahashi Go
空と大地が 交差している
Heaven and earth are intersecting
今佇んでる この世界で
In this world where I stand now
命が生まれ また沈んでく
Life is born and then sinks away again
繰り返される 営みの中
Amidst the recurring activities of life
こんなもんさと 投げ出した時
When you throw it all away, saying "this is just how it is"
夢は力を 無くす
Your dreams will lose their power
もう一度 生まれよう この場所で
Let's be born once again in this place
正義のその奥で 夢が息づいてる
Behind that justice, a dream is breathing
カッと成る魂を信じて
Believe in your soul that flares up
正義のその奥に 闇が潜んでいる
Behind that justice, darkness is lurking
見極めろ 全てを
Discern everything
振り上げた勇気は 切り裂くためじゃない
The courage you've brandished isn't for cutting things apart
引き合う絆ね
It's the bond that pulls us together
呼び覚ませ 鮮やかに
Awaken it vividly
傷ついて 行き場を無くし
Wounded and having nowhere to go
彷徨っている その魂を
That soul that is wandering
癒す力は 心の奥で
The power to heal is deep within the heart
静かに鼓動 刻んでいる
Quietly ticking like a heartbeat
持てる力 全てぶつけ
Throw all the power you have into it
涙を流すのなら
If you're going to shed tears
選ぶべき道は 君を待ってる
The path you should choose is waiting for you
見失った今を 通り過ぎた過去を
The present you've lost sight of, the past you've passed through
ハザマで諦める よりも
Rather than giving up in the gap between them
今を逸らさずに ここから始めよう
Without turning away from now, let's start from here
見極めろ 明日を
Discern the future
誰かに見せつける 勇気は脱ぎ捨てて
Cast off the courage you show off to others
素直に戻ろう
Let's return to being honest with ourselves
呼び覚ませ
Awaken it!
…ませ
...it up
鮮やかに
vividly.
紅蓮のその奥で
Deep within the crimson,
夢が息づいてる
dreams are alive,
重なる力を信じて
believe in the overlapping power.
蒼穹のその奥に
Deep within the blue sky,
闇が潜んでいる
darkness lies hidden.
見極めろすべてを
See through everything.
振り上げた勇気は
This courage I've mustered
切り裂くためじゃない
isn't for cutting through things.
引き合う絆で
With the bonds that pull us together,
呼び覚ませ
wake it up
鮮やかに
vividly.
Way to be light
On my way as soul
パプリカ
Paprika
作詞・作曲：米津玄師
Lyrics/Composition: Kenshi Yonezu
曲がりくねり はしゃいだ道
On the winding road we frolicked on
青葉の森で駆け回る
Running around in the forest of green leaves
遊び回り 日差しの街
Playing around in the sunlit town
誰かが呼んでいる
Someone is calling out
夏が来る 影が立つ
Summer arrives, shadows grow
あなたに会いたい
I want to see you
見つけたのは一番星
What I found was the first star of the evening
明日も晴れるかな
I wonder if it'll be sunny tomorrow too
パプリカ 花が咲いたら
Paprika, when the flowers bloom
晴れた空に種をまこう
Let's sow seeds in the clear sky
ハレルヤ 夢を描いたなら
Hallelujah, if we draw our dreams
心遊ばせあなたに届け
Let our hearts play and reach you
雨に燻り 月は陰り
Smoldering in the rain, the moon is hidden
木陰で泣いていたのは誰
Who was that crying in the shade of the trees?
一人一人 慰めるように
As if to comfort each and every one
誰かが呼んでいる
Someone is calling out
喜びを数えたら
When I count my joys,
あなたでいっぱい
they're filled with you
帰り道 照らしたのは
What lit the way home was
思い出のかげぼうし
the shadow of memories
パプリカ 花が咲いたら
Paprika, when the flowers bloom
晴れた空に種をまこう
Let's sow seeds in the clear sky
ハレルヤ 夢を描いたなら
Hallelujah, if we draw our dreams
心遊ばせあなたに届け
Let our hearts play and reach you
会いに行くよ 並木を抜けて
I'm coming to see you, through the row of trees
歌を歌って
Singing a song
手にはいっぱいの花を抱えて
With a handful of flowers in my arms
らるらりら
La-lu-la-li-la
会いに行くよ 並木を抜けて
I'm coming to see you, through the row of trees
歌を歌って
Singing a song
手にはいっぱいの花を抱えて
With a handful of flowers in my arms
らるらりら
La-lu-la-li-la
パプリカ 花が咲いたら
Paprika, when the flowers bloom
晴れた空に種をまこう
Let's sow seeds in the clear sky
ハレルヤ 夢を描いたなら
Hallelujah, if we draw our dreams
心遊ばせあなたに届け
Let our hearts play and reach you
かかと弾ませ
With a spring in my step
パプリカ
Paprika
花が咲いたら
When the flowers bloom
この指とまれ
Come and land on this finger
檄！帝国華撃団
作詞：広井王子 作曲：田中公平
Geki! Teikoku Kagekidan
Lyrics: Ouji Hiroi Composition: Kouhei Tanaka
引き裂いた 闇が吠え
The torn darkness howls
震える帝都に
In the trembling Imperial Capital
愛の歌 高らかに
A song of love, loudly
躍り出る戦士たち
The warriors leap forward
心まで 鋼鉄に
Even our hearts, made of steel
武装する乙女
Maidens in armor
悪を蹴散らして
Kicking away the evil
正義を示すのだ
Showing our justice
走れ 光速の
Run! At the speed of light
帝国華撃団
Imperial Assault Force
唸れ 衝撃の
Roar! With impact
帝国華撃団
Imperial Assault Force
私たち、正義のために戦います。
We fight for the sake of justice.
たとえそれが、命をかける戦いであっても、
Even if it is a battle where we risk our lives,
私たちは一歩も引きません。
we will not take a single step back.
それが帝国華撃団なのです！
That is what the Imperial Assault Force is!
街の灯が 消え果てて
The city lights have completely faded
怯える帝都に
In the frightened Imperial Capital
虹の色 染め上げて
Dyed in the colors of the rainbow
躍り出る戦士たち
The warriors leap forward
暁に 激情を
In the dawn, our passion
照らし出す乙女
Maidens shining forth
悪を滅ぼして
Destroying the evil
正義を示すのだ
Showing our justice
走れ 光速の
Run! At the speed of light
帝国華撃団
Imperial Assault Force
唸れ 衝撃の
Roar! With impact
帝国華撃団
Imperial Assault Force
走れ 光速の
Run! At the speed of light
帝国華撃団
Imperial Assault Force
唸れ 衝撃の
Roar! With impact
帝国華撃団
Imperial Assault Force
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer
君の胸の奥まで
To the depths of your heart
届くようなメロディ
A melody that seems to reach
奏でるよ
I'll play it
ハッピーシンセサイザ
作詞・作曲：BETTI
Happy Synthesizer
Lyrics & Composition: BETTI
儚く散った淡い片思い
A fleeting, pale unrequited love that scattered away
笑い話だね今となれば
It's a joke now, if you look back
見るもの全て輝いて見えた
Everything I saw looked like it was sparkling
あの日々が綺麗に笑ってるよ
Those days are smiling beautifully
我慢することだけ覚えなきゃいけないの？
Do I have to learn only how to endure?
大人になって頂戴ねならなくていいよ
If you're told to "please grow up," you don't have to
知らないことばかり知らないなんて言えなくて
Only things I don't know, but I couldn't say I didn't know
大変お似合いで嘘ついてごめんね
Saying "it suits you perfectly," I'm sorry for lying
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer
君の胸の奥まで
To the depths of your heart
届くようなメロディ
A melody that seems to reach
奏でるよ
I'll play it
つまらない建前や
Boring pretenses and
嫌なこと全部
all the unpleasant things
消してあげるから
I'll erase them for you
この音で
with this sound
何の取り柄もない
I have no redeeming qualities
僕にただ一つ
The only thing I have
少しだけだけど出来ること
is something I can do just a little bit
心躍らせる
Making your heart dance
飾らない言葉
with unadorned words
電子音で伝えるよ
I'll convey them with electronic sounds
好きになること理屈なんかじゃなくて
Falling in love isn't about logic
こじつけなんていらないんじゃない？
We don't need forced excuses, do we?
時代のせいと諦めたらそこまで
If you give up saying it's the fault of the times, that's it
…と、踏み出さなくちゃ
...if I don't take a step out,
何も始まらない
nothing will ever start.
ごめんね　遅れてる？
Sorry, am I late?
どこまで話したっけ
How far did we get in our talk?
驚いた私も　書き落としてた
Even I was surprised, I'd forgotten to write it down.
心の裏側をくすぐられてるような
It feels like the back of my heart is being tickled.
惹かれ合う二人に幸せな音を
A happy sound for the two of us drawn together.
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer,
ほらね　楽しくなる
see, it's getting fun.
涙拭うメロディ　奏でるよ
I'll play a melody to wipe away your tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない？
It's okay to not act tough, isn't it?
別に自分に素直になればいい
You just have to be honest with yourself.
何の取り柄もない僕に　ただ一つ
For someone like me with no saving grace,
少しだけ自信持てること
there's just one thing I can be confident in.
ちょっと照れるような　単純な気持ち
A simple feeling that's a bit embarrassing,
全精一杯で伝えるよ
I'll convey it with all my might.
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer,
君の胸の奥まで
reaching deep into your heart,
届くようなメロディ　奏でるよ
I'll play a melody.
つまらない建前や
Dull pretenses,
余計なこと全部　消してあげるから
unnecessary things, I'll erase them all,
この音で
with this sound.
何の取り柄もない僕に　ただ一つ
For someone like me with no saving grace,
少しだけ自信持てること
there's just one thing I can be confident in.
心躍らせる　飾らない言葉
Unadorned words that make the heart dance,
全精一杯で伝えるよ
I'll convey them with all my might.
ハッピーシンセサイザ
Happy Synthesizer,
ほらね　楽しくなる
see, it's getting fun.
涙拭うメロディ　奏でるよ
I'll play a melody to wipe away your tears.
強がらなくたっていいんじゃない？
It's okay to not act tough, isn't it?
別に自分に素直になればいい
You just have to be honest with yourself.
何の取り柄もない僕に　ただ一つ
For someone like me with no saving grace,
少しだけ自信持てること
there's just one thing I can be confident in.
ちょっと照れるような　単純な気持ち
A simple feeling that's a bit embarrassing,
全精一杯で伝えるよ
I'll convey it with all my might.
おな～い！みんな～！
Onai! Everyone!
ここまでどうだった～？
How has it been so far?
今日ねMCね、ほとんどなしでね
Today, there's been almost no MC sections,
ずっと歌いっぱなし、踊りっぱなしで来たのだけれど
I've been singing and dancing non-stop until now.
そう、気づいたのら！
Yes, you noticed!
今日はね、いつもねライブにお呼びするゲストではなく
Today, instead of the usual live show guests,
珍しいねゲストを呼ばせていただきました
I invited some rare guests.
まず最初はね、おかゆんと歌って
First, I sang with Okayun,
次、はあちゃまと歌って
next, with Haachama,
マリンちゃとも歌って
then with Marine-cha,
ポルポルとも歌って
with Pol-Pol too,
まあいつものスバルもいるけどね
and well, the usual Subaru was here too.
というね、なかなかな、珍しいなメンバーで歌ったと思うんだけど
I think I sang with a pretty rare group of members,
みんなどうだったのら～？
so how was it for everyone?
いいよね。なんかたまにはこういうのもいいと思うのらね
It's good, right? I think it's nice to do this once in a while.
なんかね、ちょっといつもとは違うメンバーで歌えて
Being able to sing with members I don't usually sing with,
ルーナもすごい楽しかったのら～
Luna had a lot of fun too!
みんな来てくれてありがとね
Thanks to everyone for coming.
そして、ここで、なんと！お知らせがあります
And now, I have a big announcement!
まずは一つ目！
First of all...
誕生日記念グッズが出てまーす！
My Birthday Celebration Goods are being released!
デデン！あ、可愛い
Ta-da! Oh, how cute!
なんかもう、なんか、すでにかわいいので溢れているのらね
It's already overflowing with cuteness!
なんなのらこれ
What is this? Incredible.
まずは一つ目。デデン！
First is this. Ta-da!
かんざきパパ描き下ろしな、B2タペストリーなのらな
A B2 tapestry illustrated by Kanzaki-papa!
こちらはなんとね、ルーナの新衣装を着て
On this, I'm wearing my new outfit,
トゥルーナイトであるね
looking like a True Knight.
みんなに指輪をね、授けているところなのらよ
It's a scene where I'm bestowing rings upon everyone.
めちゃかわいいのらな
It's so cute!
そのトゥルーナイトの証である、誓約の指輪
And the proof of a True Knight, the Promise Ring.
こちらもな、ルーナの王冠に、お星様、三日月、
This also has my crown, a star, and a crescent moon,
あとルーナイトの剣もついてる、すごいかわいいねデザインにしていただきました
as well as a LuKnight's sword. They made a really cute design for me.
こちらね、首から下げるチェーンもついてるのでね、ぜひ使ってほしいのらな
It comes with a chain to wear it around your neck, so please use it!
こちら。ルーナの髪の色と一緒、ルーナ色のね、タンブラーになってるのらな
Next, this Luna-colored tumbler, which matches my hair color!
ルーナの顔もプリントされているのでね、こちらもな、みんな使ってほしいのらや
It has my face printed on it too, so I hope everyone uses this as well.
デデン！チャーム付きスマホリング！
Ta-da! A smartphone ring with a charm!
チャーム付きスマホリング
Charm-equipped Smartphone Ring
こっちもめちゃくちゃ可愛いなな！
This is also super cute!
王冠に三日月に、もうあれ、全部ついてるからね
The crown and the crescent moon, they're all included!
こちら、チャームついてるから、みんな、こう、取り外ししてね
It comes with charms, so you can detach them...
バッグにもつけることもできるしね
...and attach them to your bag!
スマホリングとしてね、使ってほしいなな
Please use it as a smartphone ring.
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
そして、こちら、フルセットでね、ご購入いただいた方には
And for those who purchase the full set,
ルーナたんの直筆サイン＆箔押しの複製メッセージ入り
you'll receive Luna-tan's handwritten autograph and a foiled duplicate message...
かんざきパパ描き下ろしのポストカードをお届けします
...on a postcard illustrated by Kanzaki Papa.
みんな是非ね、購入してみてくださいなな
Everyone, please consider buying it!
そして、もう一つお知らせがあります
And I have one more announcement.
なんと！ルーナたんのオリジナル新曲第2弾！
Luna-tan's second original new song!
本日の24時に各種音楽サイトでリリースされるのななー！
It will be released on various music sites at 24:00 today!
ではね、最後にお披露目したいと思います
Now, I'd like to perform it for the first time.
それでは聴いてください
Please listen to it.
ぐるぐる@まわる@まわルーナ
Guruguru@Mawaru@Mawaruna
作詞・作曲・編曲：立秋
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Risshuu
まわる まわる まわルーナ
Round and round, round goes Luna
まわる まわる まわルーナ ルルナ
Round and round, round goes Luna, Lu-Luna
まわる まわる まわルーナ
Round and round, round goes Luna
まわる まわる 地球ぐるぐる
Round and round, the Earth spins round
またたくまに街中が
In the blink of an eye, the whole town...
まわる まわる あたまクラクラ
...spins round and round, making my head dizzy
幕が上がり 祭りの始まり
The curtain rises, the festival begins
回れ 回れ 舞を披露
Spin, spin, performing a dance
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning, spinning, spinning, spinning more
(もっともっと)
(More, more)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って みんなぐるぐるぐるっと回って
Spinning, spinning, everyone spin round and round
(もっと)
(More)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning, spinning, spinning, spinning more
(もっともっと)
(More, more)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って ずっとぐるぐるぐるっとまわルーナ
Spinning, spinning, spin round and round with Luna forever
(やぁ)
(Yeah!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って もっとぐるぐる笑って
Laughing, laughing, laughing, laughing more
(もっともっと)
(More, more)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる踊って みんなぐるぐるぐるっと踊って
Dancing, dancing, everyone dance round and round
(もっと)
(More)
ぐるぐるぐるぐるそうやって もっとぐるぐる回って
Just like that, spin, spin, spinning more
(ずっと)
(Forever)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って ずっとぐるぐるぐるっとまわルーナ
Laughing, laughing, spin round and round with Luna forever
(やぁ)
(Yeah!)
回りすぎたら 世界の暗闇が
If we spin too much, the darkness of the world...
みんなを包む 狂乱 でも大丈夫
...will envelop everyone in frenzy, but it's okay
ルーナが守るから
Because Luna will protect you
回る地球は 回り始め
The spinning Earth begins to spin...
いく億年
...for billions of years
いつまでも このまま
Forever, just like this
回る みんなに幸せを
Spinning, bringing happiness to everyone
回りつづける まわルーナ
Luna keeps on spinning
ますますますます世界が ぐるぐる
More and more, the world spins round
(あれっ)
(Wait?)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning, spinning, spinning, spinning more
(もっともっと)
(More, more)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って みんなぐるぐるぐるっと回って
Spinning, spinning, everyone spin round and round
(もっと)
(More)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning, spinning, spinning, spinning more
(もっともっと)
(More, more)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って ずっとぐるぐるぐるっとまわルーナ
Spinning, spinning, spin round and round with Luna forever
(やぁ)
(Yeah!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って もっとぐるぐる笑って
Laughing, laughing, laughing, laughing more
(もっともっと)
(More, more)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる踊って みんなぐるぐるぐるっと踊って
Dancing, dancing, everyone dance round and round
(もっと)
(More)
ぐるぐるぐるぐるそうやって もっとぐるぐる回って
Just like that, spin, spin, spinning more
(ずっと)
(Forever)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる笑って ずっとぐるぐるぐるっとまわルーナ
Laughing, laughing, spin round and round with Luna forever
(やぁ)
(Yeah!)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning, spinning, spinning, spinning more
(もっともっと)
(More, more)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って みんなぐるぐるぐるっと回って
Spinning, spinning, everyone spin round and round
(もっと)
(More)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっとぐるぐる回って
Spinning, spinning, spinning, spinning more
(もっともっと)
(More, more)
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って ずっとぐるぐるぐるっとまわルーナ
Spinning, spinning, spin round and round with Luna forever
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って もっと
Spinning, spinning, spinning more
ぐるぐるぐるぐる回って んま～
Spinning, spinning, spinning, nmaa~
ぐるぐるまわる まわルーナ
Spinning round and round, round goes Luna
(やぁ)
(Yeah!)
出演
姫森ルーナ
Cast
Himemori Luna
赤井はあと
Akai Haato
大空スバル
Oozora Subaru
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
天音かなた
Amane Kanata
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
撮影・企画補佐 尾丸ポルカ
Shooting/Planning Assistant: Omaru Polka
カバー株式会社
COVER Corp.
イラストレーター
Illustrator
天川さっぐ
Amakawa Saggu
ロゴクリエイター
Logo Creator
柊椋
Hiiragi Ryo
振り付け制作
Choreography Production
まいどん（おでんガールズ）
Maidoon (Oden Girls)
企画
Planning
姫森ルーナ
Himemori Luna
総合演出
General Direction
姫森ルーナ
Himemori Luna
尾丸ポルカ
Omaru Polka
協力
Cooperation
ルーナイト達
Lu-knights
監督
Director
姫森ルーナ
Himemori Luna